Khanh Q. Ngo

(857) 600-8439 | khan.ngo@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

A highly motivated and independent IT professional with 20 years of experience in fast paced enterprise environments in financial, insurance, tourism, and e-Commerce, experienced across Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including planning, development, testing, configuration management, and deployment, and a strong passion for automation for scalability, increased efficiency, and reduction in manual processes.

TRAINING:

Platform by Per Scholas (April 2019 - Aug 2019)

Java Full-Stack Web Developer Program | Cambridge, MA

Training covered exploration on how to be efficient in Agile-Scrum project methodologies using Jira. Managed databases requiring SQL and learned how to install, configure, connect, query with MariaDB. Additional topics included collections, basic I/O, JDBC, JPA, Spring MVC, and Spring Boot.

General Assembly (March 2017 – June 2017)

Web Development Immersive Program | Boston, MA

Full Stack web development program focusing on ES6 JavaScript, Bootstrap, JSON, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, Rails, Node, Express, Ember, React.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL, GIT, problem-solving, planning, modeling, and maintaining applications with client-API architectures.

EXPERIENCES:

TJX Companies (02/18/2020 – 3/23/2020**)**

Web Operations Engineer (Contractor) | Framingham, MA

- Supported, monitored, and maintained critical web-functionality of 24/7 e-Commerce sites
- Initiated GitFlow branching/merging strategy to improve speed, efficiency, and scalability of the build process
- Collaborated with Rackspace to review Jenkins pipeline to streamline the Continuous Integration (CI) practices
- Supported the software development life cycle and Agile development methodologies
- Leveraged Application Performance Management (APM) and web analytics tools such as Splunk, AppDynamics, Google Analytics, and Omniture / Adobe Analytics
- Gained valuable experience with Oracle ATG, Endeca, OMS, ESB e-Commerce platform

Leisure Pass Group (September 2019 – February 2020)

Software Application Support Engineer / Java developer | Boston, MA

- Built and Maintained Continuous Integration with CircleCI and Bamboo to build, test, and deployment
- Managed, and performed deployment of software components into lower and Production environments
- Troubleshoot compile and build failures, and facilitated resolution
- Proven ability to excel working within in 2-weeks sprint iterative agile development environment
- Acquired AWS certification and increased working knowledge with EC2, ELB, S3, and RDS
- Utilized JUnit for unit testing, IntelliJ for static analysis, and Clover for code-coverage tools for Java
- Developed React and Java code using Git with repositories in GitHub
- Heavily use SQL against MySQL and NoSQL for MongoDB to manage app and troubleshoot issues
- Implemented API test automation test automation for Postman, JMeter
- Worked to continuously identified opportunities for automation and operational efficiencies

Vestmark (June 2018 – September 2019)

Systems Engineer (Managed Services Team) | Wakefield, MA

- Monitor, troubleshoot, and triage system health and database backups related issues
- Troubleshoot issues across the stack (hardware, network, applications, database, storage)
- Implemented production changes while adhering to standardized change control protocols
- Utilized APM tools to monitor, track trends, and proposed solutions to recurring issues

- Monitor and resolve any nightly MS SQL databases backups issues
- Developed automation scripts using PowerShell for internal monitoring and alerting

Liberty Mutual Insurance Group (2011 – 2018)

Software Developer | March 2017 – June 2018 | Boston, MA

- Produced clean and reusable software in fail-fast, rapid iteration, greenfield, Agile development environment
- Obtained mastery of Git source control management system for repositories hosted on GitHub and bitbucket
- Utilized Selenium 2.0 WebDriver, Jest, Enzyme, and Cucumber for functional test automation
- Created and maintained continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) process documentation
- Achieved success in transforming the renewal experience for the personal insurance market

Senior Software Systems Engineer | October 2011 – March 2017 | Boston, MA

- Designed clear, comprehensive system, technical and infrastructure solutions in the monitoring space, that supported current and future direction
- Reviewed major infrastructure designs from a monitoring perspective to ensure consistency, maintainability and flexibility with respect to overall system, technical and product architectures within a market
- Worked effectively with senior systems engineers, developers, software owners (IT and business customers), production support teams, project managers, and senior managers
- Provided 24x7 support for IBM's Websphere Application Server (WAS6.1, 7.x, 8.x), IBMIHS, Weblogic, IIS, Tomcat, Siteminder, LDAP, BigIP, Teradata, Splunk, AppDynamics, Introscope

State Street Corporation (2000 - 2011)

Application Support Engineer | November 2008 – October 2011 | Westwood, MA

- Maintained, monitored, and supported UNIX/Linux Apps with Oracle Database servers
- Performed Oracle Database Administration (DBA) tasks to monitor and maintain system health
- Reviewed and tuned SQL queries to increase system performance
- Managed the deployment of software components into QA, UAT, Pre-Prod, and Production environments
- Developed scripts on Solaris Unix and Red Hat Linux using bash and ksh to automate App management

Trade Application Engineer | September 2007 – November 2008 | Boston, MA

- Supported and maintained trading applications and infrastructure
- Monitored electronic trade and FIX activities for immediate mitigation and resolution
- Worked with Trading Desk, Market, and Middle Office to resolve any trade issues

Data Center Operations Night Shift Manager | September 2004 – September 2007 | Quincy, MA

- Technical Support Manager for the night shift Open Systems support in 24x7 environment
- Responsible for staff selection, training and development, and performance reviews
- Maintained staffing and resource management for major data centers in Massachusetts
- Lead problem management, post mortem analysis, and root cause analysis

Application Support | June 2001 – September 2004 | Boston, MA

- Provided 3rd tier support for a real-time enterprise online data delivery application in 24x7 environment
- Deployment Management responsibilities including planning, implementation, and reporting
- Created and maintained shell and Perl scripts via AutoSys jobs for automation
- Fulfilled Business Continuity Manager (BCM) needs to track resources during emergency situations

Network Operating Center Communications Analyst | April 2000 – June 2001 | Quincy, MA

- Supported over 6,000 Solaris, AIX, HP UNIX/NT enterprise servers and applications world wide
- Monitored system health and application functions
- Active involvement in problem diagnosis, escalation, and resolution

CERTIFICATION:













